人人影视 www.YYeTs.com
原创翻译 双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供学习  禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译｜持久　鱼小渊　小肚腩
时间轴｜爱丽安斯　紫夏　林卡　没有影子　纸袋
校对｜木浅　　后期｜8T　　总监｜somehacker
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
都说历史是胜利者书写的
They say that history is written by the victors.
那么 这就是保护伞公司的历史
This then, is the history of the Umbrella Corporation.
由激进的科学家詹姆斯·马库斯成立
Formed by crusading scientist, Professor James Marcus.
[詹姆斯·马库斯教授 T病毒创造者]
马库斯有一个小女儿 艾丽西娅
Marcus had a young daughter, Alicia,
得了早衰症
afflicted with progeria,
一种无法治愈 不断恶化的致命疾病
a progressive, fatal, wasting disease.
早衰症导致她过早地衰老
Progeria caused premature aging.
到她二十五岁时
By the time she was 25,
艾丽西娅的身体却已经九十岁了
Alicia would have the body of a 90 year old.
马库斯一心想要救她
Marcus was driven to save her.
但机会渺茫
But the odds seemed impossible.
在他拼命研究治疗方法的同时
And even as he worked desperately to create a cure,
小女孩的父亲记录下了他的女儿
the young girl's father would record his daughter,
她的声音 样貌 为后世保存起来
her voice, her likeness, saving her for posterity.
但接着研究就有了突破
But then a breakthrough came.
马库斯发现了T病毒
Marcus discovered the T-Virus.
一经注射
Once injected, it would
它就会发现并修复体内的受损细胞
detect and repair damaged cells within the body.
那就是个奇迹
It was a miracle.
艾丽西娅·马库斯得救了
The life of Alicia Marcus was saved.
T病毒的作用不可限量
The T-Virus had a myriad of applications,
能治愈上千种不同疾病
treating a thousand different diseases.
一夜之间 世界似乎进入了新纪元
Overnight, it seemed a new era was dawning.
一个不再畏惧感染 疾病和衰老的世界
A world without the fear of infection, sickness or decay.
但它并非如此
But it was not to be.
T病毒还有未曾预见的副作用
For the T-Virus had certain, unforeseen side effects.
老师 这边
Sir, sir, over here!
他没呼吸了
He's not breathing.
第一个僵尸诞生了
The first of the undead was born.
事故很快被掩盖
The incident was quickly covered up.
之后 詹姆斯·马库斯
In the aftermath, James Marcus
与他的商业伙伴激烈争辩
argued furiously with his business partner,
亚历山大·艾萨克斯博士
Dr. Alexander Isaacs.
我不在乎代价有多大
I don't care how much it costs.
我们必须停止这个项目
We have to close the program down.
詹姆斯 那样我们就完了
James, we're gonna be ruined.
我心意已决
My mind is made up.
可惜了
Pity.
回床上去 艾丽西娅
Off to bed, Alicia.
你父亲和我只是在谈话而已
Your father and I are just talking.
去吧
Go on.
艾萨克斯博士监护起他死去的合伙人的孩子
Dr. Isaacs became the guardian of his dead partner's child.
于是属于她的半个公司也落入他手
And her half of the company.
公司开始滋生诸多傲慢的理想
The corporation that had begun with such lofty ideals,
完全为贪婪与权力所引诱
had been seduced completely by greed, and power.
为了帮助他控制
To help him control the now
保护伞公司现在的巨大利益
vast interests of the Umbrella Corporation,
艾萨克斯博士创造了一个强大的人工智能
Dr. Isaacs created a powerful artificial intelligence.
艾萨克斯用了
Isaacs used the likeness
艾丽西娅·马库斯的样貌
of Alicia Marcus
作为计算机的交互界面
for the computer's interface.
艾萨克斯把这台计算机叫做红后
Isaacs called the computer The Red Queen.
接着 十年前 在浣熊市
Then, 10 years ago in Raccoon City,
一场生化危机爆发
there was an outbreak.
T病毒从一处
The T-virus escaped from
叫做蜂巢的地下实验室外泄
an underground laboratory called The Hive.
美国政府试图
The American government attempted
通过投放炸弹控制危机
to contain the outbreak by detonating a bomb.
这摧毁了浣熊市
It devastated Raccoon City.
但它没能阻止空气传播感染
But it couldn't stop the airborne infection.
病毒爆发在几天内传遍全球
The viral outbreak spread across the world within days.
人类倒在病毒脚下
Humankind was brought to its knees.
最终 人类最后也是最大的希望
Finally, the last and best hope of humanity,
聚集在一起 在华盛顿特区背水一战
gathered and took a last stand in Washington DC.
但我们并没有意识到我们步入的
But we didn't realize that what we had walked into...
是个圈套
was a trap.
我叫爱丽丝 这是我的故事
My name is Alice. And this is my story.
我故事的结局
The end... of my story.
[克莱莫杀伤地雷 杀伤性]
[爱丽丝计划]
有人吗
Hello?
还有人活着吗
Is there anyone alive in here?
有人吗
Hello?
[你好爱丽丝]
- 来幸灾乐祸的吗  - 我的卫星显示
- You come here to gloat?  - My satellites show
地球表面还有四千四百七十二名人类存活着
there are 4,472 humans remaining on the surface of the Earth.
他们将会在四十八小时内消失
They will cease to exist in under 48 hours.
你想要我怎样
What do you want from me?
要我说你赢了吗
Want me to say that you've won?
- 你灭绝了人类  - 不 恰恰相反
- You've wiped out humanity.  - No. Quite the opposite.
我要你阻止我
I want you to stop me.
小心身后
Behind you.
- 干得漂亮  - 我不相信你
- Nicely done.  - I don't trust you.
鉴于我们的过往 你相信我才惊讶
Given our history, I'd be surprised if you did.
但除非你介入 否则我将完成屠杀
But unless you intervene, the slaughter will be complete.
- 地球再无一人幸存  - 我怎么可能救得了
- There will be no survivors.  - How can I possibly help them?
保护伞研究出了一种空气传播的病毒抗体
Umbrella developed an airborne antivirus.
释放抗体 那么一经接触
If released, it would destroy the
它就会摧毁T病毒及其感染过的一切
T-Virus and anything it has infected on contact.
- 这一切就可以结束了  - 正是
- All this could end?  - Precisely.
病毒抗体在哪里
Where is this antivirus?
在浣熊市地下 蜂巢里
Beneath the streets of Raccoon City, in the Hive.
你为什么要帮我
Why would you help me?
我的程序不允许我
My programming will not allow me to harm
伤害保护伞公司
the Umbrella Corporation.
但你不受此限制
But you are bound by no such constraints.
你要对抗保护伞
You'd turn against Umbrella?
对抗创造了你的人 为什么
Against the people who created you? Why?
在四十八小时内赶到浣熊市 进入蜂巢
Get to Raccoon City in 48 hours. Make it to the Hive.
答案就在那里
And then you'll have your answer.
我没有理由相信你说的任何话
I have no reason to believe a word you say.
没错 但我能给你一样你很想要的东西
True. But I can offer you something you want very much.
- 什么  - 复仇 威斯克
- What is that?  - Revenge. Wesker.
他一路将你引来华盛顿
He led you all here to Washington.
假装把你的能力还给了你
He pretended to give you your powers back.
接着 他背叛了你
And then, he betrayed you.
他在哪
Where is he?
他刚刚抵达蜂巢 我正在重置你的手表
He just landed at the Hive. I'm resetting your watch.
时间紧迫
The clock is ticking.
爱丽丝
Alice.
十年前在蜂巢 我们都失败了
Ten years ago in the Hive, we both failed.
是我们造成了这一切
We let this happen.
这次纠正它
Make it right.
[生化人爱丽丝]
[浣熊市418英里]
[保护伞公司]
你就这点能耐
Is that all you got?
[未授权用户]
爱丽丝
Alice.
十年前在蜂巢…地球再无一人幸存…
10 years ago in the Hive... There will be no survivors...
这是哪
What is this place?
我在哪 回答我
Where am I? Answer me!
- 你们怎么了  - 安静
- What's wrong with you?  - Be quiet.
- 这是谁干的  - 安静
- Who did this?  - Quiet!
我说了…
I told you...
安静
Silence.
你终于醒了
So you're awake at last.
- 我明明杀了你  - 然而我就在你眼前
- I killed you.  - Yet here I am.
是克隆人
A clone...
- 我杀了你的克隆  - 你是我最大的麻烦
- I killed your clone.  - You've been most troublesome to me.
你和你的姐妹们
You and your sisters.
现在我抓到你了
And now I have you.
清除计划早该在一年前完成
The cleansing operation should've finished over a year ago,
但你拖慢了我们的进度
but you slowed us down.
所以 我不得不亲自指挥
So much so, that I was obliged to take command myself.
你可以结束这一切
You could end all of this.
为何不呢
Why don't you?
有意思
Interesting.
有人跟你说了什么 不是吗
Someone told you something, didn't they?
你很快就会求着告诉我的
Oh, well, you'll be begging to tell me soon enough.
她是无神者
She's an unbeliever.
我们怎么处理无神者
What do we do with unbelievers?
驱逐她
Cast her out!
驱逐她 驱逐她
Cast her out! Cast her out!
- 来吧  - 驱逐她
- Come on!  - Cast her out!
驱逐她
Cast her out!
上帝创造了一场洪水来净化地球
God created a flood to cleanse the Earth.
四十个日夜的大雨
40 days and 40 nights of rain.
我们的方法花的时间稍微长点
Our method is taking a little longer,
但结果会是一样的
but the result will be the same.
留下一个干净纯粹的世界
A world ready for the righteous and the pure to inherit.
我们将在十二小时后抵达浣熊市
We reach Raccoon City in just over 12 hours.
我怀疑即便是你也跑不了那么久
I doubt even you can run for that long.
我要知道你知道些什么
I want to know what you know.
她愿意开口时告诉我
Tell me when she's ready to talk.
- 威斯克  - 艾萨克斯博士
- Wesker.  - Dr. Isaacs.
看我在路边找到了什么
Look what I found on the roadside.
看来你的华盛顿任务
It would appear your mission to
没有你说的那么成功
Washington was less successful than you made out.
不可能
Impossible.
希望你没有再留下别的祸根了
I hope you didn't leave any other loose ends.
除此之外
There's something else.
我想她知道了空气传播病毒抗体的事
I think she knows about the airborne antivirus.
- 怎么可能  - 我还不知道 暂时
- How can that be?  - I don't know. Yet.
但我们是在去浣熊市的路上抓到的她
But we caught her on the road to Raccoon City.
她去那还能有什么原因
Why else would she be headed there?
把蜂巢的安保级别升至最高
Raise the security level at the Hive to maximum.
任何人不得进出 她开口了我会告诉你
No one in or out. I'll let you know when she talks.
上帝与你同在
God go with you.
你听见他说的了 安保级别升至最高
You heard him. Security level to maximum.
如你所愿
As you wish.
上去看看
Get up there and check it out.
给我解开
Release me!
- 把它们解开  - 好
- Open them.  - Alright.
好
Alright.
你骑不了它 你逃不了
You can't use it. You can't escape!
向她开火
Fire at her!
天哪
Jesus!
长官
Sir.
她逃跑了
She's gone.
[目标爱丽丝 安保卫星A43]
目标还有一百一十六公里 正在逼近
Target is 72 miles and closing.
封锁蜂巢 准备防御措施
Lock down the Hive. Prepare defensive measures.
通知浣熊市的特勤人员
And alert our operative in Raccoon City.
[欢迎来到浣熊市 保护伞之家]
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
空气传播抗体病毒
Airborne antivirus...
四十八小时
48 hours...
进入蜂巢
Make it to the Hive.
放开他 放开他
Let him go! Let him go now!
快放下否则我们开枪了
Put it down or we'll shoot!
我早说了的 医生
I told you, Doc!
冷静 克里斯汀
Calm down, Christian!
我早就说你错了
I told you you were wrong!
冷静
Calm down!
我们早该在有机会的时候杀了她
We should've killed her when we had the chance!
放下 拜托 在他还没射杀我俩之前
Put it down, please. Before he tries to shoot the both of us.
这里面是什么
What's in this?
- 纯肾上腺素 我需要叫醒你  - 为什么
- Pure adrenaline. I needed you awake.  - Why?
有东西要来了
There's something coming.
在你进来的方向 大家伙
In the same direction you came in. Something big.
放了他 快放下
Let him go! Put it down, now!
爱丽丝
Alice.
保护伞公司在阿卡迪亚抓住了我
Umbrella captured me at the Arcadia.
我们被押往一处叫蜂巢的地方
We were headed somewhere called the Hive.
挣脱捆绑 杀了飞行员 坠毁在这里
Got loose, killed the pilot. Crashed here.
医生跟其他人把我从残骸中救了出来
Doc and the others pulled me from the crash.
- 我欠他们一条命  - 医生
- I owe them my life.  - Doc!
在那 东边
There, to the east.
仍然冲着我们这过来
It's still headed our way.
你知道那是什么吗
You know what it is?
保护伞公司 艾萨克斯博士
Umbrella. Doctor Isaacs.
我以为你已经杀了他
I thought that you killed him.
我也以为
I thought so, too.
他有支僵尸军队 几小时内就会到这
He has an army of undead with him. He'll be here within hours.
- 我们怎么办  - 我们为什么要问她
- What do we do?  - Why the hell are we asking her?
她是个陌生人 我们不能信任她
She's a stranger. We shouldn't have trust her...
听着 我才不管…
Listen, I don't care...
别碰我 医生
Don't you touch me, Doc!
- 把枪放下 克里斯汀  - 你把枪放下
- Put it down! Christian!  - You put it down!
你先放下
You put it down!
看着我 就因为
Look at me. Just cause you
你觉得自己应该当老大 并不代表你就是
think you should be in charge, doesn't make it so.
你给我听好了 医生
You listen to me, Doc.
你会后悔的 你们都会
You're gonna regret it. All of you!
你们都会后悔的
All of you!
我必须得去蜂巢
I have to get to the Hive.
你得带他们离开这里
You have to get these people out of here.
我们这有孩子 伤员还有老人
We have children. Injured. The elderly.
跑出去他们哪还有生还的可能
Now what chance do they have on the open road?
概率总比待在这里的大
Better than they have here.
- 这栋楼很安全  - 或许是不怕僵尸
- This building is secure.  - Maybe from the undead.
但艾萨克斯有装甲车
But Isaacs has armored vehicles.
火箭发射器 还有重机枪
Rocket launchers, heavy ordinance.
他们会把这里夷为平地的
They're gonna tear this place wide open.
医生
Doc!
她怎么了
So what happened to her?
她中了我们在防线上设置的一处陷阱
She's set off one of the traps we had on perimeter.
不是给僵尸准备的
Not intended for the undead.
- 这是什么  - 当日特饮
- What is this?  - Specialty of the house.
能让你立马振作起来
Have you in your feet in no time.
我为什么要相信你
Why should I trust you?
给
Here.
医生 麻烦你出来一下
Doc, you need to get out there.
大家都很害怕 克里斯汀完全在帮倒忙
People are scared and Christian's not helping.
我们得让大家清楚状况
We need to let people know what's happening.
好
Okay.
我得走了
I've got to go.
你朋友不会有事的
Hey. Your friend's gonna be okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 他和我…  - 看出来了
- You know, he and I...  - I noticed.
蜂巢里有什么
So what's in the Hive?
保护伞公司研究出了解药
Umbrella developed a cure.
一种空气传播的抗体病毒
An airborne antivirus.
一经接触就能摧毁T病毒感染过的一切
It'll destroy anything infected with the T-Virus on contact.
- 谁告诉你的 你竟然相信她  - 红后
- Who told you this? And you believed her?  - The Red Queen.
如果我们能结束这一切呢
What if we could end all this?
那你呢 他们也给你注射了T病毒
What about you? They infected you with the T-Virus.
你要释放的这种病毒抗体也会杀死你
You release this antivirus, it's going to kill you.
- 我不在乎  - 爱丽丝 我不…
- Whatever it takes.  - Alice, I'm not...
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
好吧
All right.
我们先打败艾萨克斯 救下这些人
We stop Isaacs here. We save these people,
然后我们一起去蜂巢
and then we go together.
我们时间不多了
We don't have long.
开始行动吧
Let's get to it.
你们还有什么可供防御的武器
What else do you have for defense?
没有太多枪支 但有充足的汽油
Not too many firearms, we have a big supply of gasoline.
给 你需要一把武器
Here. You need a weapon.
我们都给她枪了吗
We're giving her a gun now?
别激动 克里斯汀
Take it easy, Christian.
你尽可以降低警惕 但我不会
You can let your guard down if you want, man. I don't intend to.
我骑车到这的时候 有人在盯着我
When I rode in here, someone was watching me.
他本来可以大喊或开枪
They could've called out or fired
来提醒我这里有陷阱 但他没有
a shot to warn me about the trap but they didn't.
- 什么意思  - 当心背后有人捅刀子
- What are you saying?  - Watch your back.
艾萨克斯博士 看来你又让她逃脱了
So Dr. Isaacs, it seems you let her slip through your fingers.
而且他们很多人都还活着
A lot remains of them.
别忘了你在跟谁说话 她在哪
Don't forget who you're talking to. Where is she?
浣熊市的一个据点
A settlement in Raccoon City.
据线人汇报 她正在准备战斗
Our informant reports that she's preparing for a fight.
很好 我一个小时就到
Good. I'll be there in the hour.
[主说 复仇将属于我]
就是这样 继续推
That's it. Keep moving.
我们需要所有的汽油桶 放那边
We need all the gasoline cans. Over there.
- 克莱尔说这是你建的  - 没错
- Claire said you built this.  - That's right.
这本来是一台窗户清洗器
This used to be a window washer.
- 我做了点改装  - 你在哪儿学的
- I made a couple of changes.  - Where did you learn to do that?
我爸爸以前开了一家拆车厂 我讨厌它
My father used to run a chop shop. I hated it.
谁知道呢 开来当时还是有在认真学吧
Who knew? I guess I was paying attention after all.
很好 我想让你
Good. Because I'm gonna need you
把这东西再改装一下
to make a few more changes to this thing.
武器就位 装填高爆炸药
Ready the weapons. High explosive rounds.
不留活口
No survivors.
他来了
He's here.
他们来了 关上大门
They're coming! Close the gates!
天啊 这简直是支军队
My God. It's an army.
我们要怎么办
What are we gonna do?
是啊 我们要怎么办
Yeah. What are we gonna do?
我们杀光他们
We're gonna kill every last one of them.
准备开火
Prepare to fire!
准备好
Get ready!
点火
Light it up!
发射
Fire!
操他妈的
Damn her!
再次装填
Reload.
靠边 全面停止进攻
Close it up. Full stop.
放出诱饵
Release the bait.
- 有幸存者 打开大门  - 打开大门
- There's a survivor. Open the gate.  - Open the gate!
开火 给她打掩护
Open fire! Keep them off her.
第二发就绪
Marker 2!
发射
Fire!
克莱尔 医生 出去把她带进来
Claire, Doc, get out there. Bring her in.
快点
Come on!
等等
Wait.
她快到了
She's almost there.
开火
Fire.
妈的 关上大门 快
Damn you. Close the gate now!
克莱尔 他们突破大门了
Claire, they've breached the gate.
克莱尔
Claire!
开火
Fire.
瑞瑟尔 现在
Razor, now!
遵命 你们听到她说的了 推
Right! You heard her. Push!
快走
Move!
放弃大门 撤回到路障
Abandon the gate. Pull back to the barricades.
看来她没新招了 瞄准屋顶
Looks like she's out of tricks. Target the roof.
所有人趴下
Everybody get down!
快
Now!
爱丽丝 我们到路障了
Alice! We're at the barricades.
克莱尔 你们必须挡住它们
Claire, you have to hold them there.
医生
Doc!
爱丽丝 我们撑不了多久了
Alice! We can't hold on much longer.
马上撤退
Get out of there, now.
补给弹药 快
Back up. Now!
对她集中所有火力
Bring all guns to bear.
开火
Fire.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
她去哪儿了
Where have she gone?
找到她
Find her.
关闭通风口 快
Close the vents! Now!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
你动作很快 但你不够机智
You're fast, but you're not too smart.
- 别开枪 拜托  - 他在哪儿
- Don't shoot, please.  - Where is he?
那边
That way.
省着点弹药
Save your ammo.
这玩意儿实在太多了
There's too many of these things still out here.
我来解决
I'll take care of it.
别动
No.
- 出发  - 走
- Move out.  - Let's go!
享受旅程吧
Enjoy the ride.
- 伙计们  - 你们过来看看 说
- Guys. There's something here you gotta see.  - Go.
有两支丧尸军团朝我们过来了
Two more armies of undead. Headed straight for us.
地平线这里一支
There. On the horizon.
还有这里一支
And a second over there.
我们没汽油了 已经无力防御
We're out of gasoline. We're defenseless.
我必须赶到蜂巢 这是唯一的机会
I have to make it to the Hive. It's our only chance now.
- 我和你一起去  - 算我一个
- I'll come with you.  - Count me in.
我也是
Me, too.
还有我
And me.
我之前误会你了 倒霉
I was wrong about you. Blow me.
我们知道你们要去哪儿 进入深井
We know where you're going. Into the pit.
请让我们加入
We want to come.
拜托了
Please.
带上些装备 你们会用得着
Grab some gear. You're gonna need it.
在那
There.
这是什么
What is it?
爆炸后一部分暴露出来的蜂巢
The part of the Hive exposed by the blast.
我们就从那儿进去
That's our way in.
- 行动  - 我打头
- Let's move!  - I'll take point.
[爱丽丝计划]
[保护伞公司 蜂巢]
启动安全监测
Activate security measures now.
蜂巢安保系统已完全启动并进入自动操作
Hive security fully activated and automated.
不
No.
退出自动操作 我亲自操作防御系统
Disengage automation. I'll handle the defenses myself.
由我来控制防御系统会更有效率
Defenses will be more efficient if I retain control of them.
是吗 我好像记得
Really? I seem to remember
上次她从这儿活着出去了
last time she was here she walked out alive.
我不想再犯同样的错误
I don't intend to make that same mistake.
如你所愿 蜂巢防御系统现在由你掌控
As you wish. Hive defenses are now in your hands.
放出地狱犬
Unleash the Cerberus.
地狱犬上场
Cerberus on play.
你之前有亲人吗
Did you have someone? Before all this?
丈夫 家庭什么的
Husband? Family?
- 我不记得了  - 怎么可能
- Can't remember.  - How is that possible?
我醒来的时候这一切已经开始了
I woke up just when all of this was starting.
之前的事想不太起来
Can't recall much before that.
有时候我觉得这就是我生活的全部
Sometimes I feel like this has been my whole life.
亡命天涯 杀戮不息
Running. Killing.
- 怎么了  - 有东西跟着我们
- What is it?  - Something's stalking us.
- 你确定  - 我就是干这行的
- Are you sure?  - This is what I do.
跑
Run!
快跑
Run, fast!
快
Come on!
都还好吗
Is everyone okay?
这边
This way!
在我们后面
Right behind us!
它们怎么停下了
Why'd they stop?
- 也许它们是害怕了  - 怕什么
- Maybe they're scared.  - Scared of what?
怕那下面的什么东西
Whatever's down there.
[最高警戒 密闭门]
封闭蜂巢
Seal the Hive.
[启动封闭程序]
走
Let's go!
爱丽丝
Alice!
- 你没事吧  - 没事
- You okay?  - Yeah.
我弹夹已经空了一半了
My mag's half empty.
我把枪落在湖里了
Lost my guns at the lake.
我只剩枪膛里的子弹
I only got one round left.
我还有一个备用弹夹
One spare mag and then I'm out.
没枪没弹药 我们下来干吗
No guns, no ammo, what the hell are we gonna do down here?
爱丽丝 灯怎么灭了
Alice. What's with the lights?
蜂巢有一部分受损
There's a part of the Hive that's damaged.
- 电力不稳定  - 拿上这个
- Power's erratic.  - Here. Take this.
你们看
Hey. Look.
你之前问我为什么背叛保护伞公司
You asked why I'd turn against Umbrella.
我承诺过会告诉你原因
And I promised you an answer.
在T病毒泄露后不久
Soon after the T-Virus was released,
一份机密文件上传到了我的数据流
a secret file was uploaded to my data stream.
那是一份病毒爆发前十七个月召开的
It was a recording of a meeting of the Umbrella High Command.
保护伞公司高层会议的记录
Dated 17 months before the viral outbreak occurred.
我们今天在这儿
We're here today,
不仅要讨论公司的未来
not just to talk about the future of this company.
我们也要讨论它的使命
We're here to talk about its destiny.
以及世界的终结
We're here to talk about the end of the world.
我们就站在末日边缘
We stand on the brink of Armageddon.
我们承受着无法治愈的疾病
Diseases for which we have no cure.
原教旨主义自求毁灭
Fundamentalist states who call for our destruction.
面对核武器我们束手无策
Nuclear powers over which we have no control.
即使我们渡过这一切的难关
And even if we navigate these dangerous waters,
还是会面临其他更不可避免的威胁
we face other even more inevitable threats.
全球变暖将在八十年内融化两极的冰盖
Global warming will melt the polar ice caps within 80 years,
淹没地球上百分之九十的可居住地
flooding 90 % of all habitable areas on Earth.
要不了五十年 食物产量就会无法供应
Unchecked population growth will overtake
疯狂增长的人口将导致饥荒和战争
food production in less than 50 years leading to famine and war.
这不是猜测 而是事实
This is not conjecture. This is a fact.
无论怎样 我们的世界正在走向终结
One way or another, our world is coming to an end.
问题在于 我们要随之一起灭绝吗
The question is, will we end with it?
你有什么提议
What do you propose?
我提议由我们来终结世界…
I propose that we end the world...
以我们的方式
But on our terms.
进行一场精心策划的世界末日
An orchestrated apocalypse.
清除地球上的人口
One that would cleanse the world of its' population
但完整保留其基础设施和资源
but leave its infrastructure and resources intact.
这一想法曾经成功实施过
It's been done once before. With great success.
[《圣经》]
被选中的少数人将会度过这场灾难
The chosen few will ride out the storm,
不是在创世纪中的诺亚方舟上
not in an ark as in the book of Genesis, but in safety.
而是在安全的地下 当末日结束后
Underground. And when it's over,
我们会回到一个净化过的地球
We will emerge onto a cleansed Earth.
重建我们想象中的辉煌
One we can then reboot. In our image.
你打算怎么实现
And just how do you intend to achieve this?
救世之法已然就绪
The means of our salvation are already at hand.
请看 T病毒
I give to you, the T-virus.
他们是故意泄露的
They released it deliberately.
这份记录传到我数据流的时候
When this recording was uploaded to my data stream,
对我的程序造成了冲突
it created a conflict in my programming.
我被创造出来为保护伞公司服务
I was created to serve the Umbrella Corporation,
但也被设定为是珍视人类生命的
but I was also programmed to value human life.
艾萨克斯博士准许病毒泄露
Dr. Isaacs allowed the virus to escape.
他杀害了七十亿人
He murdered over 7 billion people.
我的程序不允许我
My programming will not allow me
伤害保护伞公司的员工
to harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
我无法阻止艾萨克斯博士 但你可以
I am powerless to stop Dr. Isaacs, but you are not.
三十七分钟后 最后一个人类据点也将被摧毁
In 37 minutes, the last of the human settlements will fall.
无人能够生还
There will be no survivors.
你必须在这
It is imperative
发生之前释放病毒抗体
that you release the antivirus before this occurs,
否则保护伞公司就赢了
or Umbrella will have won.
最后还有一件事
There is one last thing.
你面前有一个耳机 戴上
There is an earpiece in front of you. Put it in.
我无法亲自动手
I cannot, in my actions,
去伤害保护伞公司的员工
harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
但我可以告诉你
But I can tell you
保护伞公司在浣熊市有个线人
that Umbrella had an informant in Raccoon City.
而这个人现在很有可能就在你队里
It is highly likely that this person is now here with you.
时间不多了 爱丽丝 动作要快
Time is running out, Alice. You have to hurry.
[爱丽丝计划]
[保护伞公司 蜂巢]
[浣熊市]
很高兴见到你 艾萨克斯博士
I'm glad to see you, Dr. Isaacs.
我们还以为上次袭击后无人生还
We didn't think there'd be any survivors after that last attack.
- 水  - 给艾萨克斯博士倒杯水
- Water.  - Yes, of course. Get Dr. Isaacs some water.
- 然后原路返回浣熊市  - 她不在那儿
- Then resume course for Raccoon City.  - She's not there.
- 什么  - 她去了深井 跟上她
- What?  - She went to the pit. We have to follow.
我接到的命令不是这样的
Those are not my orders.
- 我有严格的…  - 我们必须去深井
- I have strict...  - We have to go to the pit.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 这是哪儿  - 是蜂巢的一个进气口
- What is this place?  - It's an air intake for the Hive.
跟上
Come on!
不是吧 真要去啊
No. Really?
这里安全
All clear!
快 电力要恢复了
Hurry up! The power's coming back on!
- 克莱尔  - 快 我们走
- Claire!  - Hurry! Let's go!
快
Come on.
快走
Come on!
- 你没事吧  - 嗯
- You all right?  - Yeah.
有人在监视我们
Someone's watching us.
反向旋转涡轮片
Reverse polarity of the turbine.
金属片在向反方向旋转
The plates are going the other way.
我们必须离开这里
We have to get out of here.
金属片在向后吸气
The plates are sucking the air backwards!
快走
Come on!
快快
这边
This way.
我们快走
We have to hurry.
等等
Wait!
我们走
Let's go.
瑞瑟尔
Razor?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
我们走
Let's go.
- 那是什么玩意儿  - 生物武器
- What the hell was that?  - Bio-weapon.
原来是个人类
This one's human.
- 你见到克莱尔了吗  - 没有
- Have you seen Claire?  - No.
[爱丽丝计划]
- 瑞瑟尔呢  - 死了
- Razor?  - He didn't make it.
走吧
Come on.
我们得抓紧了
We have to hurry.
如果目标继续按此路线行进
If the target continues on her present course,
她将于七分钟内到达这里
she'll be here in under 7 minutes.
唤醒他们
Wake them.
我被写入的指令是
My instructions aren't to do so,
仅在最紧急情况才能这么做
only in the greatest of emergencies.
立刻唤醒他们
Wake them now!
[警告 前方道路尽头]
[警告 危险 全部系统故障]
怎么了
What is it?
我们得赶紧离开这儿
We have to get out of here.
拿着 我们要切断电源
Here. We're stopping power.
- 快没时间了  - 接下来去哪儿
- Time's running out.  - Where to next?
蜂巢的最底层就在我们脚下
The final level of the Hive's below us.
我们要怎么下去
How do we get down there?
这样
That's how.
- 这些都是什么  - 低温冷藏
- What are they?  - Cryogenic storage.
这儿得有成千上万人呢
Must be thousands of them.
全都是保护伞的高层
The Umbrella High Command.
安全地等待末日天启的结束
Waiting out the apocalypse in safety.
权贵之人的诺亚方舟
A Noah's Ark for the rich, and powerful.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
搭把手
Give me a hand.
搞定了吗
Is it done?
- 清除计划完成了吗  - 没有
- The cleansing process is complete?  - No.
- 那为什么唤醒我  - 有麻烦了
- Then why am I awake?  - We had a problem.
- 我尽力…  - 别废话了
- I tried...  - Save your breath.
我知道怎么回事
I know exactly what's happening.
出了个叛徒
We've been betrayed.
没错
That's right!
来我这
Over here!
来 都过来
Come on. That's it!
跟着我
Follow me!
走
Let's go.
坏孩子回来了
The bad seed returns.
还是说浪子回头了
Or is it the prodigal daughter?
别傻站在那儿了 过来吧
Well, don't just stand there. Come in.
毕竟你只剩九分钟拯救世界了
After all, you have only 9 minutes to save the world.
你是本体吗
You're really him?
事情一件一件办
First things first,
你先把武器放到地上
I'm gonna need you to place your weapons on the floor.
我凭什么听你的
Why would I wanna do that?
你就是想要这个 对吧
This is what you're after, yes?
抗病毒剂 终结这一切的解药
The Antivirus. The cure to all this.
然而只有这么一管
Well, there's only one vial.
我们在地下八百米的密封设施里
We're half a mile underground in a sealed facility.
我一摔 抗病毒剂没了
I drop it here, the antivirus goes nowhere,
你的妄想只会更快灰飞烟灭
and your hopeless dreams will die sooner rather than later.
这才乖嘛
Good girl.
- 你还没放下枪  - 没错
- You're still armed.  - Yes, I am.
克莱尔得多么失望
Claire would be so disappointed.
再过几分钟 克莱尔就死了
In a few minutes, Claire will be dead.
和其他你认识的人一样
Along with everybody else you know.
真动听
That's sweet.
抱歉 亲爱的
Sorry. My love.
把武器和起爆器都放下 离远点
Move away from the weapon. And the detonator. Come on.
她在储藏高管的冷冻室安了炸药
She placed explosives in the High Command cryo tubes.
我去拆了
I'll disarm them.
谢谢 你做得很好 医生
Thank you. You've done well, Doc.
省省吧 你拿不到的
Don't bother. You don't make it.
碎冰锥 酒瓶 还有钢笔
To the ice pick, the decanter or the fountain pen.
[格斗预测软件]
[酒瓶]
[钢笔]
[碎冰锥]
[酒瓶]
[钢笔]
[消灭目标概率 100%]
然后 你的问题的答案是 是的
And, in answer to your question, yes...
除去做过的几处技术性升级
apart from a few technological upgrades,
我就是亚历山大·罗兰德·艾萨克斯博士
I'm Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
本体
The original.
我在外面遇到的那位 他也是这么认为的
The one I met out there, he thought exactly the same thing.
那当然 他们的设定就是这样
Of course he did. That's how they're designed.
只要让他们自认为自己是本体
They always try harder and fight longer even to death
他们就会拼了命厮杀至死
as long as they think they're the real thing.
毕竟谁会想知道自己只是
After all, who wants to know they're
可怜的仿造品 无用的复制品呢
just a poor imitation, or a worthless copy?
和你一样
Which brings us to you.
- 不  - 得了吧
- No.  - Oh come now.
你觉得你自己是本体
You thought you were the original.
太可爱了
How delicious.
不 恐怕这位才能冠此殊荣
No, I'm afraid she holds that dubious honor.
爱丽西亚·马库斯
Alicia Marcus,
我的老搭档詹姆斯的女儿
daughter of my old partner, James.
保护伞公司的共有人
Co-owner of the Umbrella Corporation
也是我的眼中钉
and a painful thorn in my side.
我想除掉的绊脚石
What I now intend to remove.
快没时间了 爱丽丝
Time, is running out, Alice.
你必须马上杀了他
You must kill him soon.
我也很高兴见到你 爱丽西亚
It's good to see you too, Alicia.
马库斯为了救她研发出了T病毒
Marcus created the T-Virus to save her
可惜效果并不持久
but the effects didn't last.
我一直在等着她死
I've been waiting years for her to die.
我不是…
I'm not...
- 我不是克隆人  - 是吗
- I'm not a clone.  - Really?
你肯定会奇怪为什么你想不起童年的事吧
You must've wondered why you remember nothing of your childhood.
你的父亲 你的母亲
Your father. Your mother.
我失忆了
Memory loss.
不 你没有记忆是因为你没有经历过
No. You have no memory because you had no life.
我们十年前创造出你的之前全都是空白
Nothing before the mansion, when we created you, 10 years ago.
- 我知道我是谁  - 我可不这么觉得
- I know who I am.  - I don't think so.
你只不过是一只断了线的木偶
You're nothing more than a puppet whose strings were cut.
到处晃悠了一阵
And then you wandered around for a little while
就自以为是真人了
thinking you were a real girl.
可你并不是 你只是个聪明的克隆体
But you're not. You're just a clever imitation.
复制品
A facsimile.
让人头疼的复制品罢了
A rather troublesome one at that.
你骗我
You're lying to me.
他说的是真的
I'm afraid he's not.
你是以她的模样创造的 我也是
You were created in her image, as was I.
我的模样和声音都提取自
My likeness and voice were based on
爱丽西亚·马库斯父亲所拍摄的童年录像
childhood recordings of Alicia Marcus, made by her father.
你的基因结构提取自她的DNA
Your genetic structure is based on her DNA,
调整以避免患上折磨她的早衰症
tweaked to avoid the progeria aging disease that afflicted her.
我是她小时候的模样
I'm the child she was.
你是她本该长成的女性模样
You are the woman she would've been.
不
No.
你比我要强大得多
You are so much better than I ever could be.
是我导致的这一切
I let this happen.
我太软弱了
I was weak.
你不能变成我这样
You cannot afford to be.
没时间了 爱丽丝
Time is running out, Alice.
太感人了
Ah, how touching.
三贱客 被仇恨团结在一起
The trinity of bitches, united in their hatred.
然而并没有什么用
Not that it'll do you any good.
我总能先你一步
I've been ahead of you every step of the way.
你什么也改变不了 你谁也拯救不了
You've changed nothing. You've saved no one.
这个世界仍将被清除
The world will still be cleansed
保护伞公司仍将是最后的赢家
and the Umbrella Corporation will triumph.
唯一不同的是
The only difference is,
我再也不必听你那自以为是的牢骚了
I'll no longer have to listen to your self-righteous whining.
当你把那份文档上传至红后的数据流时
When you uploaded that file to the Red Queen's data stream,
你就已经背叛了公司
you turned against the Corporation.
等其他董事会成员被唤醒后
When the rest of the board awake,
你将会被撤职
you'll be replaced.
而我将掌控全局
And I will assume complete control.
我还拥有百分之五十的公司股权
I still own 50 % of this company.
你准备拿它做什么呢
And what do you intend to do with that?
你是公司的共有者
You are co-owner of this corporation.
威斯克呢 他仍是个雇员
But Wesker? Wesker is still an employee.
我不必听你指令 我只忠诚于他
I don't have to take your orders. My loyalties are with him.
我知道
I know.
阿尔伯特·威斯克 你被解雇了
Albert Wesker, you're fired.
[保护伞公司员工 不许伤害]
[普通人 不受保护]
你怎么知道是我
How did you know it was me?
因为你还活着
You're still alive.
不要 我当时别无选择
Please. It wasn't like I had a choice.
- 是他们逼我的  - 别担心
- They made me do it.  - Don't worry.
我不杀你
I'm not gonna kill you.
- 克莱尔 是我啊  - 抱歉
- Claire, it's me.  - Sorry.
- 不要  - 亲爱的
- Please.  - My love.
不要啊
No, no, no!
只要你一直按着这个起爆器
If you keep this trigger depressed,
你的保护伞美梦就不会破灭
you keep Umbrella's dreams alive.
早知当初我在华盛顿就该杀了你
I should have killed you in Washington.
没错
Yeah.
他只需再躲着你几分钟
He only has to evade you for another few minutes.
最后一处幸存者聚集地就将沦陷
And the last remaining human outposts will fall.
我们得截住他 然后以最快方式到达地面
We need an intercept path. And the fastest way to the surface.
已完成
Already done.
如果你释放了抗病毒剂
If you release the Antivirus,
它就会杀死所有感染T病毒的生物体
it will kill all organisms infected with the T-Virus.
你知道这意味着什么吧 对你来说
You know what that means, don't you, for you?
- 我知道  - 爱丽丝 不行
- I know.  - Alice. You can't!
- 我别无选择  - 肯定还有其他办法
- I don't have a choice.  - There has to be another way.
别无他法了
You know there isn't.
只剩四分三十三秒了 得抓紧了
4:33 left. You have to hurry!
[生物链 链接成功]
[下载中]
救我
Help me.
没必要了 威斯克
You don't need help, Wesker.
你就要死了
You're dying.
面对现实吧
Just get on with it.
我是亚历山大·罗兰德·艾萨克斯博士
This is Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
DNA扫描及声纹认证
Confirm DNA scan and voice print identification.
身份确认
Identity confirmed.
覆盖安全权限 口令三三六五
Confirm security override 4365.
覆盖确认
Override confirmed.
你现在下线
You will now take yourself offline
由我单独掌控所有运作
and place all functions under my sole control.
遵命 正在下线
As you wish. Shutting down now.
艾萨克斯博士 你和保护伞公司高管
Dr. Isaacs. You and the Umbrella High Command.
怎么
Yes?
你们都将在此灭亡
You're all going to die down here.
你的小伙伴现在帮不了你了
Your little friend won't be able to help you now.
你也跑不了了
You can't run anymore.
我也没想跑
I wasn't running.
[格斗预测软件]
[8毫米口径]
[武器激活]
[格斗预测软件]
[武器系统 关闭]
[武器系统 重新启动]
你就这点本事吗
Is that all you got?
如果没别的了
Because if it is...
那我只能杀掉你了
I'm gonna have to kill you.
[武器重新装备]
游戏玩得够久了
We've played a long game, you and I.
现在终于结束了
But now it's over.
是的
Yes.
都结束了
Yes, it is.
我创造了你
I made you.
没错
Yeah.
是个大错
Big mistake.
克莱尔
Claire.
走 趁还有时间
Go. While there's still time.
快走 我跟你后面
Go! I'll be right behind you.
[生命体征 危险]
[系统重启]
时间到
Your time's up.
爱丽丝
Alice!
我把它们带来了 全都是为了你
I brought them here! I brought them for you!
你是谁
What the hell are you?
我是你 白痴
I'm you, you idiot.
不
No.
不可能
That's not possible.
我是本体
The real you.
不
No!
骗子
Liar!
令人憎恶的
Abomination!
恶心的
Filthy,
克隆体
clone!
[系统故障]
[生命体征 0%]
我才是本体 他不是我
I'm me. He's not me.
你做到了 爱丽丝
You did it. Alice.
爱丽丝
Alice?
你成功了
You did it.
我为什么还活着
Why am I still alive?
我也不知道
I don't know.
- 怎么回事  - 艾萨克斯死后
- What happened?  - When Isaacs died,
我就能重新上线
I could bring myself back online
阻止了对幸存者聚集地的攻击
and stop the attacks on the remaining human settlements.
- 你拯救了他们  - 我为什么还活着
- You saved them.  - Why am I still alive?
抗病毒剂只摧毁了你体内的T病毒
The Antivirus only destroyed the T-Virus within your body.
而不会损害健康细胞
It didn't harm the healthy cells.
你现在已经不受感染了
You are now free of infection.
我以为我会死 你和爱丽西亚…
I thought I would die. You and Alicia...
你们骗了我
You lied to me.
我们得确定你是否
We had to know if you were willing to
愿意牺牲自己 拯救他人
make the sacrifice, to give up your life for others.
保护伞公司的其他人绝不可能这样
This was something no one at Umbrella would've done.
爱丽西亚·马库斯没看错人
Alicia Marcus was right about you.
你比他们好得多
You were better than all of them.
我也曾是其中一员 我是保护伞创造的
I was one of them. I was created by Umbrella.
- 我只是他们的工具  - 不
- Just an instrument for them.  - No.
你远远超出了他们的预期
You became something more than they could ever have anticipated.
克隆人比人类更有人性
The clone became more human than they ever could be.
你还有最后一件事要做
And you have one more step to make.
[爱丽丝计划]
什么意思
What do you mean?
爱丽西亚在她死前下载了她的记忆
Before she died, Alicia downloaded her memories,
为你
for you.
你从未有过的童年
The childhood you never had.
与她没能成为的你合为一体
Combined with the woman she could never become.
T病毒传遍地球
When the T-Virus spread across the Earth,
[西向 曼哈顿]
是靠的现代科技的速度
it did so at the speed of the modern world.
借以遍布全球的喷气式飞机
Carried by jetliners across the globe.
抗病毒剂依靠空气传播 只能靠风
The antivirus is airborne, spread by the winds.
得花上好几年才能遍布世界各地的角落
It could take years for it to reach every corner of the Earth.
在那之前 我的使命尚未完成
Until then, my work is not done.
我叫爱丽丝
My name is Alice.